ROSIE AFIA CV

Name: Rosie Afia

Contact: rosie@afia.london I www.rosieafia.co.uk

Profile: British national I full driving license I mother tongue English, basic French & Spanish.

Highly articulate Development Management LSE graduate (MSc) with effective interpersonal skills. Experience demonstrates commitment to International Development and ability to efficiently organise, multi-task, prioritise and use initiative in the face of time-sensitive client objectives.

Experience

GSMA, Mobile for Development (M4D), London.

Oct 2014 - Current

Department Coordinator

- Support to senior management in GSMA M4D, which drives commercial mobile services in emerging markets by identify opportunities for social, economic & environmental impact.
- Responsible for assisting MD in operations & international programme management.
- Delivering professional & articulate communication with internal and external stakeholders.
- Managing and overseeing logistics and operations including in various online platforms, for example, by issuing POs or by contributing to budget processes.
- Achievements: positively driving content and operations for M4D events and supporting the Head of Disaster Response in realising programme deliverables.

Society of Business Economists (SBE), London.

Sep 2013 – Oct 2014

Project Coordinator (part-time)

- Responsible for various projects such as council proposals, meeting coordination, internal communication & report compilations on a part-time basis while completing MSc.
- Achievements: coordinating various SBE events such as master classes and AGM.

Fitch Learning, London.

Sep 2012 - Sep 2013

Client Liaison Assistant

- Bespoke courses team member for the specialist financial training company.
- Responsibilities included; general support to MD, meeting coordination, micro-project management, presentations, assistance with internal / external client contacts, course schedule administration, assistance with course feedback & contracts.
- Achievements: after undertaking a temporary marketing assistant role in 2007 & 2008 recruited to Client Liaison team. Supported senior management by temporarily acting in the more senior role as Client Liaison Officer while colleague on extended leave. Coordinated various time sensitive projects including extensive exposure to vital legal documentation.

Riad Chi-Chi, Marrakech.

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010

General Manager (temporary)

- Responsible for administration, accounts, transport, guests & staff as holiday cover for manager.
- Achievements: received excellent published reviews / feedback from guests & owner.

THAF (NGO) & African Impact (Social Enterprise), Zambia.

Jun 2008 - Sep 2009

Assistant Manager (THAF)

- Responsible for marketing, administration, accounts, operations & contracts for Zambia's sponsor-a-child scheme.
- Achievements: implementing efficient systems & procedures, including website design.
 Initiated process of providing regular feedback & updates for sponsors. Personal fundraising
 efforts totalled £4000. As a result asked to be ambassador to Kenyan programme
 responsible for contracts & service level agreements for new projects. Created proposals for
 focal projects & initiated a sponsor-a-teacher programme.

Project Designer & Coordinator (African Impact)

- Assisted local management, designed, implemented & managed the HIV & Sport volunteer project. Highly demanding, full-time & live-in job.
- Responsible for up to 30 volunteers, including organising trips to Zimbabwe / Botswana, coordinating staff, transport, visas & project administration.
- Achievements: designed HIV & Sport programme to much acclaim from community & volunteers. Founded "Livingstone Youth in Sport" charity in order to coordinate tournaments for HIV, malaria & drug awareness for children & women. As a result of the programmes success promoted to sister organisation, The Happy Africa Foundation (THAF).

Internships & Volunteer

Pro Bono Economics (Charity), London.

Sep 2014

Volunteer administrative assistant to board of directors.

Red Cross (NGO), London.

Sep 2014

Volunteer working in flagship donor shop.

Buttons for Hope (NGO), Cape Town.

Mar 2011 - Apr 2011

• Responsible for social media & press exposure for start-up NGO.

Advance Aid (NGO), Nairobi & London.

Jul 2010 & Jul 2011

Assisted CEO with proposal to the Kenyan Ministry of Health & researching potential grants.

Alive & Kicking (Charity), Nairobi & London.

Jun 2010 - Aug 2010

Coordinated 2-day event in Nairobi successfully raising around US\$10,000.

Education & Qualifications

MSc Development Management, Merit

2013-2014

London School of Economics (LSE).

Consultancy work for Crown Agents included quantitative and qualitative analysis of Public-Private Partnerships (PPPs) in Sub-Sahara Africa.

BA Economics & Politics, First Class (Hons)

2009-2012

University of Leeds.

GSMA (internal)	Industry Training (Mobile Network Operators)	Nov 2014
CodeFirst-Girls course	10-week intensive website training course	Jan 2014
Fitch short course	PowerPoint	Jul 2013
Fitch short course	Excel	Jun 2013
Fitch professional course	2-day course on analysis of sovereign & country risk in both emerging & mature markets.	Oct 2012
ONE campaigns	2-day training on running effective development campaigns.	Nov 2011

Hobbies & Other

- Software proficiency: Concur, Confluence, Dreamweaver CS6, Excel, Focalpoint, GitHub, Lotus notes, Microsoft Word, Outlook, Powerpoint, SalesForce, SalesLogix, Social Media, SohoLaunch, Sublime Text, SourceTree, Windows & Mac OS systems among others.
- Elected representative for postgraduate Development Management students (LSE).
- LSE societies: 'DESTIN', 'Business / Social Enterprise' & 'Women Leaders of Tomorrow'.
- Society of Business Economists (SBE) member since 2013.
- Keen sports woman; BASI 2 instructor (snowboarding) qualification with first aid.
- Travelled extensively in Africa, Asia, Europe & Latin America.

References available on request.